number five what is the iup pack name
for the following compound here we have
an Aline and we need to number the
parent chain so as to give the triple
bond occurring soonest so that is going
to go like this 1 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 9 now
there are a couple common errors here it
does look funny sometimes with the
triple bond there there are students
that don't realize this is a carbon and
this is a carbon some students will have
a tendency to see this just as two
carbons with a very long triple bond but
remember that carbons participating in
triple bonds are SP hybridized and
therefore exhibit linear molecular
geometry so we do have carbons 2 and
four totally 180° apart as well as three
and five so this geometry the way that
we draw this is very deliberate that is
accurately depicting the geometry of the
molecule so make sure we understand that
and